hi welcome back to the channel today I'm
going to be making a little bit
different of a video I'm going to do a
product review of something that I get
asked about
um quite a bit partially because I had
used this product probably for almost
five years ago try to test it out and
posted about it a few times which
sparked some interest from people that
follow me and most recently I've been
seeing a really really
hard push for advertising for this
product and the way that they advertise
it and the claims that they make don't
necessarily line up with my experience
with that product so what I'm talking
about are
these the victory insoles and you've
probably seen ads on this on social
media or seeing other athletes people
post about it and the claims that these
people make
are all you have to do is purchase this
product
slip it into your shoe and you will run
faster and jump higher and the reason
that they say that is because this is a
carbon fiber insole and their claim is
that it returns energy so it's allowing
you to run faster and jump higher simply
by putting this into your shoe so the
way that they do their advertising or at
least the ads that I've seen on
Instagram specifically show a guy
holding the insole like this and he
pulls the insole out and it snaps back
and hits his arm and he says that is
what we call Return of energy and then
the next thing that they do is a little
shoe test and I'm going to show you that
shoe test but also explain why that shoe
test is a bunch of
shoe test that they like to do they'll
take a normal shoe and this shoe right
now has the insole that came inside of
it so I don't have anything special in
there and then they'll take the shoe and
they'll crush it down like this
and they'll let go of it
and the shoe kind of Pops back up a
little bit and they say that's your
normal shoe now all you have to do
wrong sides of the foot
now all you have to do is slide in
the victory in Seoul
do the same thing and
the shoe Springs further than it would
be if you had your normal insulator
but here's the problem with this
when was the last time you ever saw
anybody's foot in this position
during a sport during sprinting during
running during jumping doing anything
athletically when was the last time
anybody's foot ever got into this
position
I'll tell you what if you have seen it
trust me that person ain't running
faster jumping high they're laying on
the ground waiting for a stretcher to
come take them off the field
so the reason that this is is
because
they're selling you a false hope
that all you have to do is purchase an
insole
slip it into your shoe and you're going
to automatically be faster and jump
higher without having to do a single
repetition extra in the gym without
having to put in any extra work all you
have to do is put this in and the reason
that I tested these out is because the
guy that created this company or at
least was involved with creating the
products used to be a bobsledder so he
followed along with bobsled athletes it
was my rookie year when they reached out
to me and said hey we want to send you a
pair of insoles see if you want to try
them out let us know what you think I
said sure fine so he gave them to me I
put him in my shoes
one thing I noticed really quickly is
that they made my shoe extremely
uncomfortable if you notice like the
forced Arch that it does the design of
this is that it wants to kind of Bend
right there and then snap back allow you
to get more force or jump higher as they
claim but all that really did is put my
foot in a really uncomfortable position
in my shoe and I felt immediately that I
was like striking the ground differently
or at least it felt different and that I
was running a little bit differently the
other thing that we did is we wanted to
put their claims to the test and at the
time I was living at the Olympic
Training Center and we had access to
force plates and what we would do a lot
of times either on a Monday or a Friday
we would do some Force plate testing
before our session just to kind of get
some re uh get some numbers kind of see
how well you've been adapting to your
training how those numbers go from week
a week and for a couple weeks there I
put these insoles in and did a couple
jumps and then I took them out and did a
couple jumps these insoles gave zero
additional Force output zero additional
height on my jump and because I think
the way that made my foot sit in my shoe
there was actually a couple tests where
I did worse with these in because like I
said it forces your foot to be in a
really uncomfortable position and then I
took it out put my normal insoles in and
immediately jumped higher just because
it was a more comfortable feeling shoe
and I didn't feel like my foot was in
that weird kind of like forced Arch
position using these insoles I know what
a lot of people are going to say is you
say well there's track shoes or there's
running shoes that have carbon fiber
insoles in them and it's right and there
are and I actually wear them the ones
that I wear for a lot of my warm-up
drills and a lot of like my
plyo drills have carbon fibers in them
but the carbon fiber is positioned in a
way where it allows the shoe to be stiff
you don't want extreme flexibility in
your shoe especially when sprinting you
want that shoe to be stiffer that allows
you to create hard ground contacts and
allows you to push off you don't ever
see anybody hit the ground their foot
folds and then shoots off because that's
not a strong way to apply Force into the
ground whether you're running whether
you're jumping it doesn't matter the
people who are the most explosive are
generally able to create the most amount
of stiffness throughout that lower limb
so that's why you'll see a lot of shoes
that have some carbon fiber the other
thing is the carbon fiber that's in
these shoes kind of flows with this the
way that your foot is going to be
positioned so
this shoe specifically the carbon fiber
actually comes down and then arches its
way back up kind of the natural position
that your toes want to kind of push off
them that may allow you to get a little
bit more of energy return but I think if
anything the biggest benefit that I
found from having carbon fiber in my
running shoes is I'm a bigger athlete a
lot of running shoes aren't made for
guys that are 220 pounds and that's how
much I weigh a lot of these running
shoes are designed for 130 pound
marathon runners or people who weigh 150
pounds maybe they run the 1600 meter
competitively they're not built for guys
that are 200 pounds trying to do rear
repetitions on Sprints and jumps and
that kind of stuff I've found that the
shoe that has carbon fiber in it one
stays stiffer longer so the shoe
actually lasts a little bit longer for
the amount of pounding that I can put
and two it just feels more comfortable
when doing sprints and jumps because you
have that stiffness in the shoe that you
actually want you don't want a soft shoe
that's going to be folding moving around
and bending on you as you're trying to
be doing maximal effort sprays or sled
Sprints or whatever it is and even the
track spikes that I wear these also have
a carbon fiber insole or I have a carbon
fiber plate throughout the middle of it
but again it doesn't force your foot
into that Arch position that plate kind
of bends down and then comes back up in
the toe box allowing for a natural
position and when you're doing a toe off
Sprint or anything like that the last
thing I want to say about products that
are like this is that
they thrive on selling that false hope
that you're going to immediately get
some sort of benefit from Simply making
a purchase and it was the problem with a
lot of people have when it comes to
training is they would rather spend two
hundred dollars on trying to increase
their vertical or make them jump higher
or
buy a supplement that's going to allow
them to get stronger whatever it is they
would rather spend that two hundred
dollars versus spend 200 hours training
for it and it's a lot of I see a lot of
young athletes who want everything right
now they see social media they see
people doing these amazing athletic
Feats or they see people training hard
in the gym and they want to be there
right now and I get a lot of this
because I post my training and a lot of
the stuff that I do looks like it's very
extreme or it's like the most elite
version of whatever training that I'm
doing when in reality I've been training
since I was 15 years old I've been
trying to be strong I've been trying to
be explosive and fast as I can since I
was 15. now I'm 37 that's over 20 years
of me trying to do this that's put me in
a position to do some of the things that
I can do now and this is the type of
stuff that people think is going to get
you there they don't want to put in the
work they just want to wipe their credit
card and hope that that's going to allow
them to be better so
that's my product review for the day
hope you guys liked it don't fall for
this
and get to the gym and work your ass off